{"data":[{"question":"He always _______ (say) that he will mend the window but he never _______ (do) it.","a":"says\/do","b":"says\/does","c":"are saying\/are doing","d":"is saying\/is doing","answer":"2","explain":"- We use the present simple to say how often we do things (always, never)","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"5"},{"question":"The milk _______ (smell) sour. Do you keep milk a long time?","a":"is smelling","b":"smells","c":"smell","d":"are smelling","answer":"2","explain":"- We use the present simple to say something's true in general","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"5"},{"question":"- I'm afraid I've broken one of your coffee cups.\n- Don't worry. I _______ (not like) that set anyway.","a":"am not liking","b":"don't like","c":"doesn't like","d":"isn't liking","answer":"2","explain":"- Like is not normally used in the continuous","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"5"},{"question":"He usually _______ (drink) coffee but today he _______ (drink) tea.","a":"drinks\/is drinking","b":"is drinking\/is drinking","c":"drinks\/drinks","d":"is drinking\/drinks","answer":"1","explain":"- We use the present simple to say how often you do things (usually)\n- We use the present continuous for things happening at the time of speaking","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"5"},{"question":"He usually _______ (speak) so quickly that I _______ (not understand) him.","a":"speak\/doesn't understand","b":"speaks\/don't understand","c":"is speaking\/am not understanding","d":"is speaking\/don't understand","answer":"2","explain":"- We use the present simple to say how often you do things","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"5"},{"question":"_______ you _______(hear) the wind? It _______ (blow) very strongly tonight.","a":"Do you hear\/blowing","b":"Are you hearing\/is blowing","c":"Do you hear\/is blowing","d":"Are you hearing\/blows","answer":"3","explain":"- \"hear\" is normally used in the present simple.\n- At or around the time of speaking -> present continuous (blowing).","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"5"},{"question":"The plane that you _______ (look) at now _______just _______ (take) off for Paris.","a":"look\/is just taking","b":"are looking\/is just taking","c":"looks\/takes","d":"are looking\/take","answer":"2","explain":"- Now -> at or around the time of speaking -> present continuous.","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"5"},{"question":"I always _______ (buy) lottery tickets but I never _______ (win) anything.","a":"buys\/win","b":"buy\/win","c":"am buying\/wins","d":"am buying\/am winning","answer":"2","explain":"- We use the present simple to say how often you do things (always, never)","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"5"},{"question":"_______ you _______ (know) why an apple _______ (fall) down and not up?","a":"Do you know\/is falling","b":"Do you know\/falls","c":"Are you knowing\/falls","d":"Are you knowing\/is falling","answer":"2","explain":"- Know is not normally used in the continuous.\n- We use the present simple to say something is true in general","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"5"},{"question":"He never _______ (listen) to what you say. He is always thinking about something else.","a":"listens","b":"listen","c":"is listening","d":"are listening","answer":"1","explain":"- We use the present simple to say how often you do things (never)","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"3","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"5"}]}